ARCHANA H NAIR

(+ 45 71451513

□ archana.harinair@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/archana-h-nair-0b64992a/

github.com/archana6832

archana6832.github.io/portfolio-website/

O Copenhagen , Denmark

SUMMARY

Full stack web developer with a background in Engineering teaching and mentoring. Experienced in mentoring more than 15 groups of students in their Engineering final year projects and teaching more than 500 students throughout the career. Competent in creating websites and applications from concept, layout and interactive elements to server-side and databases.

SKILLS

HTML

CSS

JavaScript

React

React Native

Bootstrap

Node

Express

jQuery

AWS Lambda

MongoDB

Puppeteer

Jest

Git and GitHub

EDUCATION

CareerFoundry

Full-Stack Development Program April 2021 - April 2022

Speak -School of Danish

Danish Language Leanring 2018 -2019 B2 -Advanced Level

T K M College Of Engineering

Masters in Engineering & Technology 2012 -2014

Second Rank in University

WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

Full Stack Developer Project | Meet app

- Developed a progressive-web application with React using a test-driven development (TDD) technique with Enzyme and Jest
- Followed test-driven-development approach, translating user stories into scenarios for unit and integration testing, acceptance testing (Cucumber) and end-to-end testing.
- Implemented serverless functions with AWS lambda to authenticate and authorize users.

GitHub Repo

Live Demo

Full Stack Developer Project | Chat App

- Developed a chat app for mobile devices using React Native that requires the use of Expo.io.
- Used Gifted Chat library to create the chat interface and its functionality and Android Studio's Virtual Device to manually view and test the app.
- Used Google Firestore Database to store chat conversations and Google Firebase authentication to authenticate users anonymously.

GitHub Repo

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Managing Partner 2015 - 2018

Fashion Jewellers and Textiles

Overall management day to day operations.

Assistant Professor 2010 -2012

Atharva College of Engineering, Mumbai, India

- Mentored students in their projects to make the submission on time.
- Assistant Head of Department.